

## Summary.

A full stack software engineer with overall 3+ years of experience in web development, past 2 years at Enphase Energy Pvt Ltd and an year of prior industry experience at a remote startup. Interested in solving business-level problems, Currently using backend in NodeJS and frontend ReactJS frameworks but flexible and willing to learn new frameworks and languages. Interested in devising a better system with new technologies and tools if the need arises.

### Education

IIT Kharagpur Kharagpur, India

B.Tech.+ M.Tech. (Dual Degree) in Instrumentaion Engineering and Signal Processing CGPA-8.34/10

(2017-2022

Bangalore, India

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### Enphase Energy Pvt. Ltd.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER July. 2022 - Present

• Orchestrated a public API infrastructure in **NodeJS Express** framework, to offer core features of Solargraf for client's CRM integration.

- Wrote extensive **unit tests** for more than 20 APIs developed using **Mocha** to build a test suite which was integrated with the CI/CD pipeline on GitHub.
- Created and maintained detailed API documentation of public endpoints provided for clients using ReactJS, using swagger documentation format in YAMI.
- Build API monitoring dashboards using Python scripts and regex pattern matching to monitor and analyse production metrics like throughput, failure rates, number of active clients, etc.
- Contributed and coordinated with a team of more than 10 people to develop a new UI written in ReactJS framework.
- Worked on other features involving subscription packages which involved writing migration files, as a part of the internationalization of SG app for multiple countries.

Blotout Inc. Remote

SERVER ENGINEER

May 2021 - Jan 2022

- Integrated a Consent Management platform by including a user consent checkbox onto their React JS Application on a data lake platform.
- Built custom dashboards using advanced **SQL**, **Superset** BI and **AWS Athena** to query databases for generating custom charts and tables of the user data.
- Used marketing tools like Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager to integrate custom events (eg. button click) to get real-time reports of
  those multiple marketing metrics, also automated their analytics platform using Python scripts and REST APIs to automatically add datasets,
  create charts and import dashboards to BI.

CityMall Pvt. Ltd. Remote

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Jan. 2022 - April=2022

- · Worked on the monitoring infrastructure where I was responsible for setting up different metrics exporters (Node Exporter, Kafka exporter, etc),
- Prometheus service monitors and creating custom monitoring dashboards on Grafana for visualizing production applications.
- Created rule based alerts on Grafana to throw alerts on Slack by monitoring error responses like 4xx/5xx on their production nginx server.

# **Key Projects**

#### Sandbox chrome extension

Feb 2024

- Built a chrome extension for clients to add their company, users and subscription plan by filling a form popup on the sandbox environment for solargraf. Added validation error messages to the extension popup form to disallow users from giving wrong inputs.
- This ad-hoc project was instrumental in removing a layer of contact where clients used to contact developers to add their companies using manual API calls.

#### Phonocardiogram (Heart Sound) Processing and Classification

Prof. Nirmalya Ghosh, IIT Kharaqpur

Masters Thesis Project

May 2021 - Feb 2022

- Segmented Heart sound of Patients into Cardiac Cycles using Signal Processing techniques like autocorrelation, enveloping and thresholding.
- Built several Deep learning Models to classify five heart diseases from the heart sound patterns generated by each due to murmurs.
- Built 2D representation of signals using **Spectrograms** and Scalograms, and applied **2dCNN** and **BiLSTM** based classification models on them.
- Currently working on event segmentation of Heart sounds to get better predictions of results and to have better understanding of the data.

JULY 15, 2024 RAHUL MALU · RÉSUMÉ 1